直すのは苦手だ
Sell out Uvo?!
実際に触らないと力が出せない
I'll take that as a yes...
ゴンもアルカも
Hold on...
俺が助ける！
Let's hear his explanation. Explanation?
これを　はずすなんて…。 私の能力じゃ　とても
Allies x And x Lies
背負いきれない。
After seeing Hisoka's fortune, Nobunaga suspects Hisoka of betraying them, and draws his sword.
ああ　これから戻る ゴンのほうは　どうだった？
Forget it. You're impossible to deal with.
[TEL]　ダメだったよ。 カイトのことを言っても 計器には何の反応も出なかった。
As if, you fool!
皆　来てくれて 声を掛けてくれてはいるが 全く反応がない。
What? Nobunaga, stop talking for a bit. Huh?
[TEL]　ああ　分かってる。 もう　まっとうな方法で 戻せるとは思えない。
Did the boss do that? Probably.
[TEL] 待て！　冷静になれ　キルア。
Hisoka, I have a few questions for you.
[TEL]　確かに　ゴンは お前の言う通り
If you're unable to answer, just say so.
「誓約」と「制約」を使って
A red-eyed customer will visit your shop,
seeking to make a trade.
The customer will use the sword of law upon you,
taking the calendar's secrets with him.
一時的に 超強力な「念」を使ったんだろう。
In the fortune, what are
the calendar's secrets?
ならば　やはり　解決するのは 除念師に任せたほうがいい。
A red-eyed customer will visit your shop,
seeking to make a trade.
The customer will use the sword of law upon you,
taking the calendar's secrets with him. The powers of the Troupe's members. Of how many members? Seven.
[TEL]　リスクを負うのは
No, eight.
やれることをやってからで 遅くないんだ！ あぁ　悪い　俺の言い方が 誤解させちまったようだな。
The boss and Uvogin, Shizuku, Machi, Franklin, Pakunoda, Shalnark, and I add up to eight.
別に　破れかぶれのギャンブル やろうってわけじゃないんだ。
So until yesterday, you didn't
know of Kortopi's ability?
[TEL]　むしろ ゴンは必ず元通りになる。
That is correct.
[TEL]　任せてくれ。
What is our opponent's power? I cannot say.
[TEL]　その意味じゃ　除念師　使うより ローリスクだよ。
What about his appearance? I cannot say.
ただ そっちに着くまでが問題なんだ。
What is your relationship to him? I cannot say.
今回　一番　難しいのは そこへ行くことだといっていい。
I understand.
[TEL]　申し訳ございません キルア様。 ゴトーか。
The red-eyed customer, the chain user, has two abilities at the very least.
これ以上の通話は 機密上　控えさせていただきます。
One would be the ability he
used to capture Uvogin.
まだ何も　しゃべってねえよ！ いいえ 「ゴンは必ず元通りになる」が
The other would be the ability that
prevents Hisoka from speaking.
アルカ様の能力の 示唆に当たります。
seeking to make a trade.
The customer will use the sword of law upon you,
taking the calendar's secrets with him. Since the fortune uses the
phrase "sword of law,"
そこは　ぎりぎり敷地内ですが
the latter must be able to compel
you to follow set rules.
すでに　キルア様の 外出時警戒レベルは
"Do not lie to me."
「４」となっておりますので ご注意ください。
"Do not give out any information about me." Something like that.
あえて　俺がモラウにヒントを 言うまで待ってたわけか 俺に甘いな　ゴトーは。
I would also assume that he placed something inside Hisoka's body.
[TEL]　はて 何のことでございましょう。
A red-eyed customer will visit your shop,
seeking to make a trade.
The customer will use the sword of law upon you,
taking the calendar's secrets with him.
レベル４か
The first half of the verse mentions a trade, but the second half only describes
what the customer took.
だいぶ　親父を 怒らせちゃったな
A red-eyed customer will visit your shop,
seeking to make a trade.
The customer will use the sword of law upon you,
taking the calendar's secrets with him.
外出時警戒レベル４
This suggests that the sword
of law would attack Hisoka.
ターゲットの言動に 禁止事項があり これを監視するため
In other words, he traded the
sword's attack for our secrets.
ターゲットを 複数の執事と家族が追尾する
Oh, so lovely...
禁止事項に抵触した場合 即時捕獲され　強制帰宅となり
The sword that can restrict Hisoka's
speech is powerful indeed.
自動的に　ターゲットの 警戒レベルは「５」となる
You are magnificent...
レベル５ ターゲットが　敷地内から 一歩でも外に出ると同時に
I absolutely must be the one to kill you. Let's review.
捕獲対象となる
We're up against the chain user.
内訳は？ [TEL]　機密物の持ち出しと 両親への 反抗的かつ威圧的な態度が
He's either a Manipulator who used
real chains to defeat Uvo, or a Conjurer who used Nen
chains to defeat him.
警戒理由となっておりまして。
Is there a difference?
アルカは　物かよ！
A big difference.
[TEL] 禁止事項が３つございます。
A Conjurer could walk around unarmed.
１　機密保持のため ターゲットは許可なく
That's a huge advantage. I see.
部外者との会話 物品の受け渡しなど 一切の接触を禁ずる。
Conjurers have to exercise their imaginations, but it's easy to conjure
something you're familiar with.
それに付随し　あらゆる 通信機器の携帯を禁ずる。
The problem is the power
that's restricting Hisoka.
[TEL]　とっくに 取り上げられてんだけど。
Since it's the sword of law, it must
involve rules he has to follow.
２　機密保持のため
Yes, it's very likely that two are the
commands the boss mentioned.
ターゲットは アルカ様の半径１ｍより
Also, he's probably barred from
attacking the chain user.
外に離れることを禁ずる。 [TEL]　はいはい　目も手も離さねえよ。
And I'd imagine that he'll die
if he breaks those rules.
３　機密保持のため アルカ様の能力に関して
How amusing. There is no sword of law in my body...
ごく一部であっても 部外者に知られることを禁ずる。
That fortune was my own creation.
ふぅ　よく分かった。
I only revealed the powers of two members.
要するに…。
Not eight.
こういうことだな。
It was a risky gamble that would have turned the entire Troupe against me,
if the boss hadn't figured that out.
これなら　いちいち 許可や確認　取らずに済むだろ。 移動中の俺らの雑事は 全部　任せたからな。
All to keep the spiders in Yorknew City, to allow me to fight the boss.
私は　ともかく カナリアも同行させるのですか？ バカ！　アルカは女の子だぞ。
Should we leave Yorknew City, it's hard to say when I'll see the boss again.
お前みたいな　おっさんに デリケートな世話ができんのかよ！
What about Hisoka's second verse?
ご安心くださいませ。 あっ。
"The eleven-legged spider grows homesick, losing five more legs.
私どもも同行いたします。
Do not leave your temporary shelter, for you are one of the remaining legs."
そちらの２人だけでは 足りぬだろうと シルバ様からの お申し付けですので。
If he leaves our temporary shelter, this base, then Hisoka will die.
ツボネ。
What does the homesick part mean? It refers to our desire to go home.
相当　おかんむりってことね。
Uvo, Hisoka, Shizuku, Pakunoda, Shalnark.
大丈夫だよ。
One more for half the members...
レベル４で むちゃなんかしないって。
No one else's fortune predicted their death?
いいこと？　キルアちゃん。
Then it has to be Feitan, Kortopi, or me. We didn't get our fortunes told
because we lacked the data.
私は　お父様やゴトーのように 甘くはありませんことよ。
I am staying here.
違反　即帰宅。
There's something I wish to do before I die.
これは絶対　譲れませんことよ。
I will not be leaving our temporary shelter.
抵抗　即失神。
Boss, what should we do?
これもお覚悟あそばせ　いいこと？
Leave or stay?
キルア様を「ちゃん」呼ばわりは 敷地　広しといえど
Stay.
ツボネ先生のみ
No.
お兄ちゃんを いじめちゃダメよ！
Huh? Why not? You were the one who wanted to
capture the Phantom Troupe.
ごめんなさい。
It'd be pointless now.
アルカちゃまは　お優しいわねぇ もう　しないわ。 今　分かった
But why? With the reward gone, you'd be
taking a big risk for nothing.
俺　ババア全般苦手なんだ
Yeah, but capturing the Phantom
Troupe would be worth it!
お兄ちゃん　好き？ 大好き！
You're getting your priorities mixed up. Have you forgotten why we're here?
はい！
Greed Island. Exactly!
キルア様が 私を頼ってくださっている
The Southern Piece auction begins in two days.
お友達を助けるため 危険を顧みず
We need to build up our war chest! Actually, I have a great plan
to get the game.
お助けする たとえ　それで仕事を…
What's your plan?
命を失うことになるとしても
It's a secret right now! Stop being coy, and spit it out...
アマネよ　よろしく。
I'm going to die! Anyway, I'll work something
out for the game.
カナリア　こちらこそ。
So for now, let's stick to the Troupe.
ツボネ。 小指の爪　頂戴。
Do you really have a plan? Yep, but it's not guaranteed to work. How likely is it to work?
ツボネに「おねだり」が！
Seventy percent. Seventy?
最悪のタイミングだ
M-Maybe more like sixty...
ナニカの「おねだり」が いつ　誰に来るかは 俺にも分からない
So it's a fifty-fifty deal. That sounds much better than trying
はい　いいですよ。
I'll let you handle the game. But we can't deal with the Troupe alone.
キルア様 私は　一時　身を隠します。
Basho and I will accompany you. Can you watch over things here, Squala? Sure.
これで　アルカ様が他の誰かに
I'm saved! Guard the Scarlet Eyes well.
「おねだり」することは できなくなりました。 私次第。
Yeah. With these guys helping, I should be fine.
この意味は分かりますことね？ もちろん　お２人のおそばからは 離れませんことよ。
I'm off, then. Yeah, see you later.
あ　まだ　あったのに…。
How did it go?
やられた！
The community didn't have any updates
regarding the auction today.
大丈夫だ まだ　俺に分がある！
You should tell them that
the Troupe is still alive!
「お願い」はできなくても 「命令」はできる！
Then the Mafia might rethink it. No, nothing will change.
ん？
The community values its
relationship with Meteor City.
お兄ちゃん　怒ってる？
It's safe to assume that they will
not attack the Troupe further.
大丈夫　アルカは 何にも心配することないよ。
My only concern is whether the
auction will proceed as scheduled...
俺が必ず　助ける
You're not planning to intercept them, are you? That's crazy...
[TEL]
I never had any help from the Mafia.
はい…　はい。
Kurapika, let us help.
ええ　そうです。
We're willing to do anything.
これは　キルア様の携帯電話です。 ん？
Turn him down... The reward was rescinded. I know.
いえ　それは申し上げられません。
I want to stop the Phantom Troupe. That hasn't changed.
それも申し上げられません。
Turn him down... Turn him down!
それを言われるなら
You'd be risking your lives.
まず　そちらが 名乗るべきじゃないんですかね。
Come on, that's what he wants to hear.
誰？ それが…。
Okay, let's put together a plan.
[TEL] [TEL]　はい。
Uh-huh. He agreed?!
こちら　レオリオと申しますが!!
First, we'll need someone to watch their base, and to provide updates.
キルアくんに 代わっていただけますか!?
I can do that. The target is the woman named Pakunoda.
シ！
You can ignore everyone else. Okay.
お　懐け
Be very careful.
お久しぶりですね　レオリオ様。
Don't worry, I won't push my luck.
[TEL]　あぁ？
I'll need a driver to accompany me.
[TEL]　あっ　分かった！ コインの野郎か！
Leorio, could you handle that? Huh?
キルア様は確かに　我々と共に そちらへ向かわれています。
Y-Yeah... It'll be fine. You'll be safe if you're with Kurapika.
ええ　ゴン様　救済のためです。
Hey, Killua... Don't make it sound like I
was scared or something!
ですが　そのためには 厳しい条件がございます。
Kurapika, what about me?
[TEL]　おい　こら！
I need you to act as a decoy,
to throw the enemy off.
[TEL]　ダチ助けんのに条件だと!? 寝ぼけてんのか!?
Got it. Hold on! Isn't that a dangerous role?
目が覚めてねえなら もっとデカい声　出すか!?
He'll have to face the Troupe members again! That depends on our strategy.
[TEL]　口を閉じろ　三下。
Strategy?
んだと　こら！
What strategy will we use? A very simple one.
キルア様は命懸けだ。 [TEL]　家族の反対を押し切って そっちへ向かってる。
While the enemy is occupied with Gon, I'll capture Pakunoda and escape by car. That sounds a little shaky...
[TEL]　ゾルディック家が特別なのは てめぇも知ってるだろ。
There are too many uncertainties
この条件は こっちが頼んでるんだ。
for me to devise a concrete plan. I'll let Gon decide his strategy.
いいから黙って聞け　この野郎。 ゴトー。
But I'll need you to draw their attention
for at least half a second... A full second if at all possible.
大変　失礼いたしました。
One second, then? Yeah.
代わって　そのほうが早いよ。
Draw their attention away for one second.
大丈夫 何も余計なこと言わねえよ。
Can I do that?
違反　即帰宅だろ？
Gon. You are the key.
よっ　久しぶり。
Can you handle it?
[TEL]　キルア　こっちへ来たら そいつと少し話させろ！
I'm not sure. I'll need to think about it.
[TEL]　おめぇは 大丈夫なんだろうな？
We have six hours.
ああ　詳しくは何も言えないけど 俺を信じて ゴトーの言う通りにしてくれ。
If the auction proceeds as scheduled, the spiders will make their move before then.
ああ　分かった　代わってくれ。
Hey, why are you accepting our help now? Because the risk I'm taking has increased.
えっと…　モラウさんだっけ？
No matter the cost.
俺が俺のケータイで 俺のダチと話してんのに 何で　あんたに 代わらなきゃいけねえんだ？
He's... So this is why Kurapika seems so different...
いい質問だ。
His resolve is even stronger.
答えは　「さっさと代われ」だ。
Kurapika, put a Nen blade in me!
嫌だね　引っ込んでな。
A Nen blade?
分かった だが　１つ頼みがある。
Gon, weren't you listening?
おそらく　お前さんは
Kurapika will die if he attacks anyone
who isn't a Troupe member!
「そんなこと　できるわけがない」と 言うだろう。 そしたら　素直にケータイ渡せ。
Keep your voice down! Then why is there a Nen
blade in Kurapika's chest?
なぜなら 俺は　できるからだ。
Kurapika isn't a member of the Troupe.
もしもし？　あぁ　何でもない 条件を言ってくれ。
What I'm about to tell you
will increase my risk further.
私どもが　そちらに 到着しましたらば
Okay.
病院の建物内は　ゴン様 一人だけにしていただきます。
Hey, Killua...
できるわけねえだろ!! 国立病院だぞ!!
I'll start with the conclusion.
It is indeed possible.
建物の中に　一体 何千人いると思ってんだ　こら!!
The five chains have different abilities.
ふぅ　ふぅ。
Two of the chains are for attacking spiders.
もしもし　条件は分かった 俺に任せてくれ。
The first is Chain Jail.
[TEL]　具体的には？
The binded target is
forced into a state of Zetsu.
デカい病院だ　駐車場もデカい。
This power is for capturing the spiders.
そこに　ゴン専用の病室を建てる。
And this is my Judgment Chain.
もちろん　車で入って 車で出られるように造る。 あんた達が中で何をしているか
I point a blade at the target's heart,
then state rules that they must follow.
絶対に分からないようにする。
If a rule is broken, the target dies.
[TEL]　承知しました 病院の件は　それで結構です。 [TEL]　あなたは？
As you've figured out,
I pointed a blade at my own heart.
[TEL]　モラウってもんだ。 次からは ぜひ　あなたと話がしたい。
At first, I devised the rule that I would die if I attacked anyone besides a spider
だとさ。
with my chains, and I set a
blade pointed at myself.
ぐぅ…。 あっ　もう１件かけるぜ。
But that was when I realized something.
[TEL] ノヴか？　俺だ 少し条件が変わった。
Would using them on myself be
considered a violation of that rule?
機材を外側の別室から 操作できるようにしてくれ。 いや　モニターはダメだ 窓も付けないでくれ。
It was possible I would be an exception, but I didn't know for sure.
確かにな。
That's why I adjusted the rule.
「誰にも見られたくない」って 条件は
I can only use Chain Jail against the spiders.
除念師っぽいっちゃ　ぽいんだが キルアの言いっぷりは違ってたぜ。
Meaning that I can use my Judgment
Chain on those who aren't spiders.
ハンター協会唯一の 除念師が　さじを投げたゴンを
But first, a condition must be met.
ノーリスクで 絶対に元に戻すと言った。
A condition? This chain can only be used
when my eyes are scarlet.
いや　これ以上の詮索は やめておこうや。
You can make your eyes scarlet now?
キルアは　「任せろ」と言った。 信じた仲間が　そう言ったら
I had to work at it. It took a while before I could
deliberately turn them scarlet.
黙って従うのが 現場のルールだからな。
I mastered the power in my middle finger
by vowing to never release this chain, and to always risk death.
モラウの旦那。 キルアとの連絡は あんたに任せたぜ。
The power in my pinky was
resolved by my unique nature.
ああ　任せろ。
When my eyes are scarlet,
I become a Specialist.
お前さんは　どうするんだ？ どうしても　ひと言
And I can use any ability I've
learned at full strength.
言っておきたい奴が多くってな。
I'm not sure what that means, but you should be able to use
your Nen blade on me, right?
[TEL]
Yes. Go ahead. You can choose the rule to set. I accept your resolve.
ゴンが　こんな状態なのに どこで何してやがる
Can you make three of those blades?
なぜ出ねえ！ クラピカ
You can rescind the rule once
our mission is over, right?
[TEL]
Killua! Leorio! We had a little talk. And since we're working together... We should share the same fate. What do you say?
というわけで 我々「十二支ん」は
The answer to both questions is yes. But you three are wholly mistaken.
前会長の意志を尊重し 今までの方針を堅持しつつ さらなる 協会の飛躍を目指すことで
I never had any intention of
using my blade on you guys.
志は　一致しております 我々の 誰に投票していただいても
Then why endanger yourself
by telling us your secret? Gon, I wanted...
その一票が無駄になることは 絶対にありません。 その点はご安心ください。
No, I wanted to thank all
of you for your resolve.
さて　一方 現在の協会に不満のある方や 上層部の一新などを 求めている方も
Even if one of you ends up revealing my secret, I will have no regrets.
しかし　できるならば 意思表示を 棄権という形で示すことを
I have good friends...
直談判でも　この場で 演説していただいても結構です。
That's not fair, Kurapika.
必要なのは 声に出していただくこと。
You're actually putting more
pressure on us this way.
我々は決して　少数の意見を ないがしろにはいたしません。
That was my goal.
現に　ここへ座っているジンは
Oh, I get it now!
年間　両手に余る規約違反を 繰り返しておりますが
That isn't remotely funny!
今もこうして　「十二支ん」の メンバーに名を連ねております。
Well, I'll head out, then.
棄権するくらいならば
Can't waste any time.
彼に　一票投じるのは いかがでしょうか？
Be careful, Killua!
あっ　笑うとこですよ。
Yeah, I got this.
我々会員　一丸となって クリアしようじゃありませんか！
You will find eternal rest in a room filled with black merchandise.
はい 副会長ありがとうございました。
Beware solitude above all.
席に戻ってくださいませ。
You have the most to fear when
you are alone with another.
とっとと。 それでは質疑応答に移ります。
On a dark day with very little light, you will face two choices within a small room.
どなたか ご意見ご質問のある方
You must choose between pride and betrayal.
挙手してくださいませ。
While the death-bringer hovers near.
はい　そこの 濃紺スーツのデカい方　どうぞ。
Do not make any phone calls.
２８７期のレオリオだ。
Let's break into groups.
そこのジンって人に 聞きたいことがある。
We'll spend the next week
operating in these groups.
あれが　ゴンの親父
Avoid moving alone. Shizuku, Pakunoda, and Machi.
なぜ　ゴンの所へ行ってやらねえ。
Kortopi, Phinks, and Feitan.
あいつが今　どんな状態か 知ってんだろ！
Nobunaga and Shalnark are with me.
はい　それでは 答えていただきましょう。
Bonolenov, Franklin, and Hisoka will stay here. Boss, can I ask a question? Some kids know about this place.
ダチだ。
Well, they didn't have anything
to do with the chain user.
そうか　世話になってるな。
But I'm still worried.
これからもよろしく頼む　以上だ。
Yeah! I forgot! Boss, I want to recruit that kid.
質問に答えろよ！ てか　行け！ ゴンの所に行ってやれよ！
Wait, that wasn't why I mentioned them!
おめぇみてぇな仲間が
Explain.
あいつには 何人かいると聞いている。 それで十分だと言っている。
I see... He does sound interesting.
ふざけんじゃねえぞ　てめぇ!!
However, it doesn't sound
like he'll join the spiders.
ゴンが　どれだけ あんたに会いたがってるか
We can convince him!
分かって言ってんのか!?
Just meet with him.
あんたが声を掛けてやれば
Boss, don't listen to him.
あいつは 元気になるかもしれねえんだぞ!!
So, Machi, why the concern?
あいつが自分から 来てほしいとでも言ったのか？
Um... It's just a hunch. Instinct, huh? You have sharp instincts.
言える状態じゃ…
It's possible that there's something
important about those kids.
この…　クソ野郎!!
Kortopi, can you make ten more? I can do another fifty. And the instant anyone enters
a fake base, I'll know.
一遍　死ね!!
There are more buildings now!
おっと！ 本日の議会の様子はですね 一部始終をハンターサイトで 見ていただけますので 皆様からも欠席者の方へ お伝えくださいまし！
As rain comes pouring down, the operation to capture
Pakunoda commences.